Mr. Chow。
The honourable.
The Honourable Horden Chow.
at the council meeting of seventh June two thousand and seven.
在接受The request of Mr. Long John Ying, the former chief executive.
Claudia Mo, move a motion under Rule Forty Nine B Bracket One A.
會廳 has completed its work and tabled its report in the council at today's meeting.
intentionaly and repeatedly make false representation at the Zetzel committee.
在我的職能作為調查委員會主席，我現在簡要介紹委員會的工作和發現。
The allegations particularised in the schedule to the central motion include, among others, the following: a.
Meeting over the origin of the proposed amendment, with the intention to mislead the select committee into believing that these amendments were raised by himself.
Mr. President, the investigation committee established under the Rule 49B, blanket 2A of the rules of procedure, in respect of the motion to censure.
of the rules of procedure, ROP, to censure the honourable Chow Ho-tung under Article Seventy Nine Bracket Seven of the Basic Law.
石禮謙議員就立法會根據議事規則第四十九B條二A條譴責周浩鼎議員嘅議案成立嘅調查委員會嘅報告，向本會發言。石禮謙議員。
had attempted to obstruct and pervert the inquiry of the select committee to inquire into matters about the agreement between Mr Loong, Chan Ying and Australian firm UGL Limited.
and this。
在 disciplinary。
Proceeding as adopted by the committee, this is.
基於的説法，如出於中央動議。
在《The Sanche Motion》 was to refer to the committee.
委員會 held a total of eight close meetings between November.
The more serious the allegation or criticism, the more compelling the evidence is required to establish the allegation of the criticism.
After thorough consideration, the committee is of the view that parts of the allegation under the first and third facts are established.
and see Mr. Chow's behaviours amount to contempt of the electoral, as well as misbehaviour and breach of oath under the Basic Law.
The committee has also made reference to the relevant overseas parliamentary rules and practices, and comparable cases of inquiry into the course of its investigation.
二零一七和二十三號六二零二零，包括兩次閉庭，由六位證人出席，為其調查工作和辯論其結論。
to ensure the investigation procedures are fair and seem to be and seem to be fair to all the parties involved, the committee has strictly observed due process throughout the investigation.
委員會已識別出四項事實須釐清，並考慮是否每項陳述所指的事件可被釐清，考慮有關的證據和資料，並根據標準證明。
As stipulated under ROP 73A, blanket two, the committee is responsible for establishing the facts stated in the censure motion and giving its view on whether or not the facts are, as established, constitute grounds for censure.
charging the committee's responsibility under 73A, blanket two, the committee have studied the relevant constitutional and statutory requirements and the relevant procedures and guidelines of the Legislative Council and its committee.
to amend the proposed major areas of study of the select committee. B. The proposed amendments submitted by Mr. Chow for discussion at the open meeting of the select committee of 25 April 2017 were in fact made by Mr. Long and Mr. Chow.
In accordance with the ROP forty nine B bracket two A, as no motion was moved at the said council meeting, that no further action should be taken on the central motion, the debate of the central motion was adjourned, and the matter.
委員會也 notes that the
程序和 privilages 委員會 of the Western Australia.
The committee considers the honourable Mr. Chow as a member of.
And that members of this select committee are not obliged to make.
Select committee and the public in believing that those amendment were raised by himself.
Representation as to who had helped them for their views or prepare amendments to the document.
立法會持相同觀點，在處理John Bowler案時。
委員會的考慮和發現，所有陳述在懲治動議中詳述，都列在報告中。
委員會，然而，由採用採 adopted 標準批准，並未考慮其他 factual 聲稱是否已確立。
to the select committee for discussion at its meeting on 25 April 2017. B. The proposed amendments was made by Mr. Lowe.
here I wish to highlight the committee's findings in respect of two such allegations, which are indeed grave allegations against the honourable Mr. Chow.
The committee and deputy chairman of the select committee should have the right to propose amendments to the proposed major areas of studies, and in the course of formulating his amendments.
The committee notes that neither ROP nor the select committee's practice and procedure expressly prohibit private communications between its members and witnesses, including the subject of inquiry.
And these facts are: a, Mr Chow has discussed with Mr Leung the proposed major area of study of the select committee, accepted Mr Leung's request to amend the major areas of study, and as a result submitted the proposed amendments.
First, I like to mention the allegation that the honourable Mr. Chow intentionally and repeatedly make false representation in relation to the origin of the proposed amendments at the meeting of the Select Committee on 25 April 2017, in order to mislead the.
委員會持有觀點，成員們應當不受限制地從廣泛的來源獲得資訊，這些資訊對於他們形成對委員會擬議的主要研究領域的修正案的基礎是很有用的。
啲committee。
委員會進一步考慮，它。
An authorised disclosure of confidential proceeding.
啊，for said allegation is established.
另一個 allegation我 wish to mention here is that the honourable Charles
on account of the above consideration, the committee does not find the
behaviours as set out in the established facts have damaged the dignity.
Mr. Bowler was found guilty of contempt of the Western Australian Legislative Assembly in the.
has also make reference to the John Bowler case to facilitate its consideration of the above allegation.
他應該有權考慮任何人士的觀點，包括有關調查對象的觀點，並有權同意或採納該人士的觀點。
And was censured for his action, which had diminished public trust in parliamentary institution and process. In drawing reference from this case, the committee has borne in mind that the document involved.
The committee notes that the proposed major areas of study was an open document uploaded on Letchmo website for public viewing and does not contain any confidential information.
autonomy and independence of LEGCO, and such damage amounts to contempt of the functions and powers of LEGCO. Has brought shame on LEGCO and seriously undermined the public confidence in LEGCO and LEGCO members.
possible that the honourable Mr. Chow genuinely subscribe to Mr. Leung's view, and thus had already adopted the proposed amendment as his own views when he submitted them to the select committee for discussion, and presented them at the said meeting open meeting.
insensitive。
基本 law can be established.
embarrass behaviour under the
Meeting or hearing held behind closed doors.
and admitted that he was polit politically incentive.
And that has led the public to have a negative perception of the incident.
They are not required to say who has drafted this amendment or have helped to form their views and quotes.
open quote members source information for debates and amendment in the house and in committee from a broad range of areas.
The committee therefore does not find that the above allegation can be established by the available evidence and information.
The committee notes that, when speaking of his way of handling the proposed amendment at the media session on 16 May 2017, Mr. Chow apologised.
Ledco， nor to bring shame on Ledco， and its behaviour are not of such gravity as to undermine the public confidence in Ledco and its member as a whole.
All his attempts to mislead the House about the origin of those comments. Indeed, it was noted by the Procedure and Privileges Committee in that case. The members, if I may quote.
On the allegation that the honourable Mr. Chow' behaviours, as described in the established fact, are in breach of legal oath taken by him at the council meeting of 12 October 2017 under Article.
在Joint Bowler case was a confidential draft committee report comprising the relevant committee's observation and outcome of the subject inquiry, while in the honourable Mr. Charles case, the select committee's document on the draft major.
Areas of study, to which Mr. Zhou's proposed amendment was openly available for public viewing on the internet. Nor did the document contain any confidential observations or deliberations made by these select committees. At its
Moreover, while Mr Bowler was found guilty of contempt of the House for the unauthorised disclosure of confidential proceedings, the House did not impose any other penalties on Mr Bowler for his non-disclosure of the source of comments on his attempt.
administrative so。
行為會 have let。
Issue by the committee on members.
in their own in their capacity as such.
have no or no meaningful impact.
是 for the select committee to decide after deliberation at open meetings.
委員會，that the sanction of this of disqualification.
for this reason, the committee does not find the said allegation can be established by the available evidence and information.
104 of the Basic Law and the oath of Declaration Ordinance, the committee considers that it is likely that Mr. Charles relevant.
利益應該是考慮是否某特定行為構成成員違反《BL七十九》條款七的元素。
One way or the other, on his promise to serve Hong Kong Special Administrative Zone conscientiously, dutifully, in full accordance with the law, honestly and with integrity.
公眾對其作為成員於選委會獨立和客觀判斷的能力產生懷疑，作為其與調查主題的溝通結果，留下公眾對事件的負面印象。然而，他的行為是。
在在委員會的觀點，而鄒先生的行為，如在已確立的事實中所描述，可能對公眾對成員的認識產生影響。他的行為並不足以達到對職權和權力的不敬程度。
Mr President, in order to give views on whether the established facts constitute grounds for the censure of the honourable Mr Jauhding, in accordance with ROP 73A, bracket two, the committee is considered whether the two allegation made in the censure motion about breach of oath.
Quite apart from this, the committee bears in mind that the proposed amendments, which according to Mr. Joe also contained his own views and were considered appropriate by him as a whole, were proposals to amend an open document, and their adoption or otherwise was.
As regards the to the second allegation that the honourable Mr. Chow's behaviours, as set out in the established facts, constitute misbehaviour under Article 79, bracket seven of the Basic Law, the committee shares the views of the previous invest.
郭榮亨議員就調查根據。
do not warrant a finding of misbehaviour under.
係 serious enough to affect the reputation of electrical as a whole.
在《The Advisory Guidelines》。 as such， the committee considers that Mr. Chow's behaviour
Basic Law 79, bracket seven. As it's not satisfied, and it's not satisfied that the second allegation can be established.
The committee has come to the conclusion that the facts as established are not sufficient to constitute ground for the censure of Mr. Chow. The committee report has been uploaded on the electoral website for public hearing. Thank you, Mr. President.
應只應只適用於當成員被發現有極其嚴重的 misconduct，而該成員的 misconduct 應該嚴重影響了 Legco 整體的聲譽。委員會也認為，帶來嚴重的不當聲譽。
立法會，and acting contrary to the generally generally assumed standard of conduct expected of a legislative member, as described in the advisory guidelines of matters of ethics in relation to the conduct of members of the Legislative Council of Hong Kong special.
委員認為，張的相關行為已對公眾對議員的認知產生了一定影響。不過，由於相關事實已經確立，委員認為沒有足夠的證據來結論張的行為。
Nor is the committee satisfied, based on its finding, that the honourable Mr. Zhou's behaviours have brought serious discredit upon Legco, or that he has acted contrary to the generally assumed standard of conduct expected of a Legco member, as described.
Mr. President, in view of the above findings, the committee is not satisfied that the honourable Mr. Zhao's behaviours as set out in the established facts constitute misbehaviour and/or breach of oath under Article 79, Section 7 of the Basic Law.